<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <string name="api_key"> AIzaSyA_PzQFAzM26Sz7LPg-Bowl2_JvxnPqxoc </string>

    <string-array name="sections">
    <item>Constant Velocity</item>
    <item>Constant Velocity Youtube Video</item>
    <item>Constant Velocity Calculator</item>
    <item>Constant Velocity Q/A</item>
    <item>Average Velocity</item>
    <item>Average Velocity Youtube Video</item>
    <item>Average Velocity Calculator</item>
    <item>Average Velocity Q/A</item>
    <item>New Section</item>
    <item>New Section Youtube Video</item>
    <item>New Section Calculator</item>
    <item>New Section Q/A</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="velocity">
        <item>Welcome! I would like to help you better understand Constant Velocity.</item>
        <item>Lets start with the definition of velocity.</item>
        <item>We say that velocity is defined as distance over time.</item>
        <item>Of course we mean the distance traveled over the time it takes to get there. So it\'s a change of time.</item>
        <item>We will see why it\'s important to think in terms of "the change of" in the definition when we talk about acceleration.</item>
        <item>Now, this certainly one way of defining velocity, but there is another way of saying the same thing.</item>
        <item>We could also say that the distance traveled is proportional to the time of travel, and velocity is the proportionality constant.</item>
        <item>Thinking of distance as the product of velocity and time allows us to visualize this idea with a picture we can draw on the blackbord.</item>
        <item>Let\'s start with trying to think about velocity in a different direction.</item>
        <item>Let\'s think of velocity as going upward. It\'s like the faster you go, the higher we are on the vertical axis.</item>
        <item>And then we think of time as going off to the right.</item>
        <item>Let\'s start with trying to think about velocity in a different direction.</item>
        <item>We can visualize all three things in just one picture drawn in two dimensions. Just as length as length times height is area in real space, velocity times time is distance in this particular way of looking at it.</item>
        <item>Let\'s look at an example. Suppose you are going 60 miles an hour. Of course that means you will go 60 miles in 60 minutes.</item>
        <item>... or one mile for each minute. Most people know that 60 miles per hour is also one mile per minute.</item>
        <item>But did you know that 60 miles per hour is also 88 feet per second?</item>
        <item>Anyway, we can think of this same velocity in terms of different distances...</item>
        <item>...depending on time. In a second you travel 88 feet.</item>
    </string-array>




    <string name="Vel_eq1"><![CDATA[ Velocity=<sup>distance/</sup>time ]]></string>


    <string name="Vel_eq">Velocity=Distance/Time</string>
    <string name="Vel5_eq">Distance = Velocity * Time</string>


    <string name="VelQA">What do you think the distance in the formula looks like in the our picture?</string>
    <string name="VelQA1">In less time you travel less distance. How far do you think you travel in 3/4 of a second?</string>

    <string name="VelQAa1">Area</string>
    <string name="VelQAa2">Volume</string>
    <string name="VelQAa3">Speed</string>
    <string name="VelQAa4">I don\'t know</string>

    <string name="VelQA1a1">88 ft</string>
    <string name="VelQA1a2">66 ft</string>
    <string name="VelQA1a3">44 ft</string>
    <string name="VelQA1a4">I don\'t know</string>


    <string name="Prev_text">PREV</string>
    <string name="Home_text">HOME</string>
    <string name="Next_text">NEXT</string>

    <string name="app_name">Infinite Blackboard</string>
    <string name="title_activity_velocity_video">Video Title</string>
    <string name="test_string">Test string</string>
    <string name="title_activity_constant_velocity_calculator">Constant Velocity Calculator</string>








</resources>
