<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Infinite Blackboard</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="Prev_text">Prev</string>
    <string name="Next_text">Next</string>
    <string name="Home_text">Home</string>
    <string name="Displacement_text">Displacement</string>
    <string name="Speed_text">Speed</string>
    <string name="Velocity_text">Velocity</string>
    <string name="Acceleration_text">Acceleration</string>
    <string name="Graphs_text">Kinematics with Graphs</string>
    <string name="OneD_text">1-D Motion</string>
    <string name="TwoD_text">2-D Motion</string>
    <string name="Formulas_text">Formulas</string>
    <string name="Review_text">Review</string>



    <string name="hometext">
 Please click the Start button to begin. You may select the menu to choose a topic.
    </string>




    <string name="question">
        A particle is moving around in a circle and its position is given in polar coordinates as x = Rcosθ, and y = Rsinθ, where R is the radius of the circle, and θ is in radians. From these equations derive the equation for centripetal acceleration.
    </string>

    <string name="displacement1">
        Let’s understand the differences between distance and displacement. Displacement is vector quantity, meaning it has magnitude and a direction. The displacement of an object that moves from point A to point B is a vector whose tail is at A and whose tip is at B.
    </string>

    <string name="displacement2">
        Distance is scalar quantity meaning it only has magnitude. The distance equals the total distance covered from point A to B. If I started from point A and travels in a circular motion and ends back at position A the displacement would equal 0, where as the distance would the circumference of the circle.  Since the displacement is a vector quantity, it is not enough to say that the displacement is 100 meters: you must also state the direction of that displacement.
    </string>

    <string name="speed1">
        In everyday use and in kinematics, the speed of an object is the magnitude of its velocity (the rate of change of its position).
    </string>

    <string name="speed2">

    </string>

    <string name="SpeedQuestion">

    </string>

    <string name="velocity1">
        Velocity is the rate of change of the displacement,Δx. It is the difference between the final and initial position of an object.
    </string>

    <string name="velocity2">

    </string>

    <string name="VelocityQuestion">

    </string>

    <string name="acceleration1">
        Speed and velocity only deal with movement at a constant rate. When we speed up, slow down, or change direction, we want to know our acceleration.
    </string>

    <string name="acceleration2">

    </string>

    <string name="accelerationQuestion">

    </string>

    <string name="twod_motion1">
        2-dimensional motion is just like 1-dimensional motion, but with two directions to consider instead of just one! With 2D motion, we must now consider both horizontal motion and vertical motion at the same time! This is often portrayed through projectile motion. Projectile motion is when an object is traveling in freefall, but is also traveling horizontally simultaneously. A projectile\'s velocity changes in the vertical direction, but remains constant in the horizontal direction.
    </string>

    <string name="twod_motion2">
        A very common example of this is shooting a cannonball out of a cannon. The path of the cannonball often follows a parabolic path that not only travels vertically, but horizontally as well! We\'ll be using the four kinematic equations to determine the displacement, time, velocity, or acceleration at any given moment during the projectile\'s motion.
    </string>

    <string name="twod_motionQuestion">
        If a cannonball has an initial velocity of 860 m/s, what distance away does the cannonball hit the ground when shot from the cannon at a 45 degree angle with the horizontal?
    </string>

    <string name="title_activity_two_dmotion">Infinite Blackboard</string>
    <string name="title_activity_two_dmotion_qa">Infinite Blackboard</string>
    <string name="title_activity_acceleration">Infinite Blackboard</string>
    <string name="title_activity_acceleration_qa">Infinite Blackboard</string>
    <string name="title_activity_speed">Infinite Blackboard</string>
    <string name="title_activity_speed_qa">Infinite Blackboard</string>
    <string name="title_activity_velocity">VelocityActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_velocity_qa">VelocityQAActivity</string>

</resources>
